# Siddhartha Singh

**CONTACT** 

Suyog Nisarg, Wagholi Pune, Maharastra **E-mail:** inbox.siddharthasingh@gmail.com

**Phone**: +91-782-748-9494

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

IT professional having **9+ years** of experience in **IBMi (AS400) Application Development and Support** roles. Worked in **Banking & HealthCare** Domain including payments and Regulatory Reporting. Experience in Software development with considerable knowledge in the analysis, design, coding & re-engineering of applications with **SDLC** and **Agile Methodologies**.

#### **SKILLS**

- Team Leadership
- Banking Domain & Payments
- AS400/IBMi
- RPGLE/SQLRPGLE
- CLLE
- DB2
- SQL
- ARCAD/Implementer
- lirs
- AWS
- Python
- Sonarqube/Smartbear
- RDi
- Java/Object Oriented Programing

WORK EXPERIENCE

# TATA Consultancy Services Ltd.

May 2016 — Present

Assistant Consultant Client: HSBC Bank

## Roles & Responsibilities:

- Working in Core Banking team that develop/enhance modules related to Payments,
  Deposit and Regulatory & Compliance for multiple countries.
- Working as SME for Unified Payments Interface (UPI) module.
- Responsible for requirement gathering, L0/L1 estimates, prepare functional design based on Initial requirement document.
- Design solution and provide technical implementation using Agile methodology.
- Coding as per the Customer Requirement, Unit Testing, Code Review and Deployment to UAT using ARCAD.
- Involved in Production release and provide warranty support for live projects.

## **Accomplishments:**

- Involved in migration of existing MQ based services to IWS microservices API.
- Developed functionality to link customer AADHAR number via various channels like staff & IVR.
- Involved in Global & country specific Regulatory Reporting projects e.g. FATCA, CRS for multiple countries.
- Modularization and decoupling of India local payment system like NEFT/RTGS.

Siddhartha Singh

**Environment:** IBMi, AS400, RPGLE, CLLE, SQLRPGLE, DB2, ARCAD, Agile, JIRA, RDi, Sonarqube, Smartbear.

## **Dell International Services**

Oct 2011 — May 2016

Software Dev Analyst

**Client: Dignity Healthcare** 

### Roles & Responsibilities:

- Requirement Analysis and preparation of Functional & Technical document.
- Coding, Unit Testing and Review as per the technical requirement.
- Working on defect Analysis & fix and provide RCA to on-shore Team.
- Providing L2/L3 Application & Batch support in various shifts.

Environment: IBM iSeries, RPGLE, CLLE, SQLRPGLE, DB2, Medseies4.

### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor Of Technology**

Jul 2007 — Jun 2011

Institute Of Engineering & Technology

Computer Science and Engineering with 73.56%

HSC Jul 2005 — Jun 2007

**UP Board** 

PCM with 73.00%

SSC Jul 2003 — Jun 2005

**UP Board** 

Science Stream with 73.00%

**HOBBIES** 

Reading, Chess, Cricket, Cooking

Siddhartha Singh